# Hugo Thimonier, PhD Multimodal Research Scientist

₹ GoogleScholar R<sup>6</sup> ResearchGate

I am a Multimodal Research Scientist at Emobot, working on ML for Audio and Video. I hold a PhD in Computer Science from CentraleSupelec focused on **deep learning for tabular data**, with a particular focus on **anomaly detection** and **self-supervised learning**.



### **Employment History**

2024 - now Multimodal Research Scientist, Emobot.

2021 – 2024 Ph.D. in Computer Science, , CentraleSupelec.
Topics: Anomaly Detection, Self-Supervised Learning, Deep-Learning for Tabular Data.

- Proposed 3 novel anomaly detection methods for tabular data: improved my project management capabilities.
- Supervised an internship and group projects for final year CentraleSupelec students: improved my **management skills**.
- Coded from scratch deep learning models in PyTorch and Python.
- Currently working on a **representation learning** for tabular data involving a novel self-supervised approach.

**Teacher** Computer Science Department, CentraleSupelec.

Course: Python (24h)

Topics Covered: OOP, Algorithmic, Data types...etc

2021 – 2022 **Teaching Assistant** Computer Science Department, CentraleSupelec.

Course: Artificial Intelligence (20h)

Topics: Machine Learning, Search Problems (e.g. Adversarial Search Problems, Local Search Problems), Markov Decision Process, Reinforcement Learning, Logic.

Deep Learning Scientist Intern, L'Oreal Research & Innovation. (6 months)

Developed a novel post-processing model to enforce temporal consistency in videos which were processed frame by frame using non-transformation equivariant imagetrained algorithms. (Paper: here, Supplementary material: here)

- Computer Vision.
- Deep learning for CV: CNN, ConvLSTM, Temporal Warping.
- Team work and Long term project management.

### **Education**

2015 - 2020

2021 – 2024 PhD in Computer Science, CentraleSupelec. CentraleSupelec.

Title: Advancing Anomaly Detection in Tabular Data: A Case-Study on Credit Card

Fraud Identification. **Supervisors**: Bich-Liên Doan, Fabrice Popineau, Arpad Rimmel.

**Jury**: Louise Travé-Massuyès, Alain Celisse, Marius Kloft, Gaël Varoquaux and Alamir Mazen.

Normalien Fonctionnaire-Stagiaire, ENS Paris-Saclay.



## **Education (continued)**

2018 – 2020 M.Sc. Engineering, ENSAE, Statistics, Probabilities and Computer Science.



2020 - 2021

Two-year University Diploma, Sorbonne University Russian. PANTHEON SORBONNE
This diploma grants me A2 level and would allows me to pursue a Bachelor in Russian.

## **Skills & Interests**

Languages French (native), English (fluent), Spanish (B1), Russian (A2)

Coding Python, LTFX, SLURM, Gitlab/GitHub, UNIX

Machine Learning PyTorch, Scikit-learn, Pandas, Numpy...

Sports Running, Tennis, Chess.

Other | Electronic music production, fly fishing.

Volunteering Mathematics teacher at Institut Villebon Georges Charpak (2019-2020).

### **Research Publications**

### **Conference Proceedings**

- H. Thimonier, F. Popineau, A. Rimmel, and B.-L. Doan, "Beyond individual input for deep anomaly detection on tabular data," in *Proceedings of the 41st International Conference on Machine Learning, ICML 2024, Vienna, Austria*, ser. Proceedings of Machine Learning Research, vol. 235, PMLR, Jul. 2024.
- H. Thimonier, F. Popineau, A. Rimmel, and B.-L. Doan, "Retrieval augmented deep anomaly detection for tabular data," in *Proceedings of the 33rd ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM '24), Boise, ID, USA*, New York, NY, USA: Association for Computing Machinery, 2024.
- H. Thimonier, F. Popineau, A. Rimmel, B.-L. Doan, and F. Daniel, "TracInAD: Measuring influence for anomaly detection," in 2022 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN), 2022, pp. 1–6.

  DOI: 10.1109/IJCNN55064.2022.9892058.
- H. Thimonier, J. Despois, R. Kips, and M. Perrot, "Learning long term style preserving blind video temporal consistency," in 2021 IEEE International Conference on Multimedia and Expo (ICME), 2021, pp. 1–6. ODOI: 10.1109/ICME51207.2021.9428445.

#### **Preprints**

H. Thimonier, F. Popineau, A. Rimmel, B.-L. Doan, and F. Daniel, Comparative evaluation of anomaly detection methods for fraud detection in online credit card payments, 2023. arXiv: 2312.13896 [cs.LG].

### **Oral and Poster Presentations**

#### **Oral Presentation**

Anomaly Detection Conference - CentraleSupelec (DataIA) (2024), Paris (Fr). Presented a synthesis of my papers Beyond individual input for deep anomaly detection on tabular data and Retrieval augmented deep anomaly detection for tabular data.

**IJCNN 2022**, Padova (Italy). Presented my paper *TracInAD*: Measuring influence for anomaly detection.

## **Oral and Poster Presentations (continued)**

**ICME 2021**, Virtual. Presented my paper Learning long term style preserving blind video temporal consistency.

#### **Poster**

- **CIKM 2024**, Boise (ID, USA). Presented our paper Retrieval augmented deep anomaly detection for tabular data.
  - **ICML 2024**, Vienna (Austria). Presented our paper Beyond individual input for deep anomaly detection on tabular data.
- NeurIPS 2023, New Orleans (USA). Presented our paper Beyond individual input for deep anomaly detection on tabular data in the Table Representation Learning Workshop.
- 2022 Symposium GDR MaDICS, Lyon (Fr). Presented current work on anomaly detection.

## References

Available on Request